Hello, I'm Tom Sloan.

I am a highly driven worker, leader, and builder who loves to be immersed in the bleeding edge of technology. With my experience as a researcher, passion of creating high impact technology, and leading teams to help exceed expectations, I am ready to jump into my next challenge. Learn more on my website: tom-sloan.com

Notable Certifications

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (SAA)

AWS Certified Developer – Associate (DVA)

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (CLF)

January 10, 2022 February 3, 2022

July 20, 2020

Notable Independent Projects

Smart Home Internet of Things, Independent Project

May 2018 – April 2020

C, C++, Python, CAD, PCB Design, AWS, Firebase

- Made a Smart Home using a Raspberry Pi using Python, and AWS
- Wrote an application that allow easy control of the IoT devices from an iPhone
- Incorporated Firebase into the iPhone application to provide authentication, storage, and machine learning capabilities
- Designed many CAD models using Fusion 360 for varying applications, including a Smart Home case, and light fixtures
- Designed, built, tested, and demonstrated many different devices that could be automated or controlled over Bluetooth and Wi-Fi with easy-to-use applications on both iOS and android operating systems
- Built numerous Internet of Things projects with a wide variety of hardware with and without Arduino using several different sensors and wireless connections methods using C, C++, and Python
- Created testing scripts of several projects using C and C++ to ensure the reliability of both the software and hardware designs

See more at: tom-sloan.com > project > Smart-Band-Project

Smart Band Internet of Things, Independent Project

May 2018 - April 2020

C. C++, Python, CAD, PCB Design, AWS

- Designed and built a printed circuit board for a fitness tracker
- Wrote software that connects the fitness tracker to the above Smart Home app, for notifications and various data points to be shared
- Used a machine learning algorithm (Support Vector Machine) to count steps and to use gestures to control the IoT devices constructed in the above project
- Used Fusion 360 to design CAD models for molds to make silicone wristbands using silicon epoxy and other parts

See more at: tom-sloan.com > project > Smart-Band-Project

Other projects

- Portfolio Website, React, Redux, JavaScript, HTML, Sass
- Twitter Bot, Python

Work Experience

Spectrum Engineering Co-Op Telesat, Ottawa **Researcher** Carleton University, Ottawa

May 2020 - April 2021 May 2018 - April 2021

See more at: tom-sloan.com > experience

Technical Experience

| Python | С | Java | JavaScript | React | HTML5 |
|--------|--------|----------|---|------------|--------|
| CSS3 | MATLAB | Three.js | NodeJS | PCB Design | Github |
| Sass | Altium | Arduino | A more comprehensive list is at tom- sloan.com | | |

Contact

https://tom-sloan.com tsloan81@gmail.com +1-613-314-7700 LinkedIn/ tomsloan7

Education

Fall 2017 – Fall 2021
Carleton University
B.S. in Computer Systems
Engineering with Distinction

Teamwork

Team Lead of a 4th Year Project titled *Smart Pillbox for Persons* with Dementia.

Report can be found at tomsloan.com > project > Smart-Pillbox

Team Lead of 4th year group project titled *Project Deep Space Sparkle*.

Report can be found at tomsloan.com > project > Deep-Space-Sparkle

Notable Awards

- Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada Undergraduate Student Research Award (\$6735)
- A. Davidson Dunton Scholarship (\$8000)
- Carleton Engineering Faculty and Design Scholarship (\$1000)

Hobbies & Misc.

- Canadian Securities Course
- Black Belt in Karate
- Royal Conservatory of Music Level 7 for piano
- Aquafitness Instructor June 2016 Dec 2017
- Lifeguard and Swimming Instructor May 2015 – Dec 2017